<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cygwin on StatSnips</title>
    <link>/tags/cygwin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cygwin on StatSnips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 StatSnips. Distributed Under a MIT License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 10:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/cygwin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with JHPCE</title>
      <link>/2017/08/08/getting-started-with-jhpce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/08/getting-started-with-jhpce/</guid>
      <description>What is JHPCE? JHPCE or the Joint High-Performance Computing Exchange is a computation resource available to members at the Johns Hopkins Medicial Institute (JHMI). Several research groups across the School of Public Health and School of Medicine tap into the power of JHPCE to run computationally expensive analyses - our transplant epidemiology group included.
The JHPCE introduction to new users describes some use cases. This blog will be a brief introduction to getting your system ready to log onto the JHPCE cluster to use Stata-MP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cygwin Colors</title>
      <link>/2017/03/10/cygwin-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 21:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/10/cygwin-colors/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered that Mintty is a great way to make your Cygwin terminal prettier. Mintty made my conversation from Fedora to Windows 10 and Cygwin more palatable.
Like all Cygwin pacakges/add-ons you’ll have to install it using the Cygwin installer. You can find some quick instructions at HowToGeek.
While there are a number of themes out there, I really like this Base-16 inspired set. I’ve also done some other tweaks to make my Cygwin terminal behave like my Mac Terminal (such as transparency when not in focus).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>