<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on StatSnips</title>
    <link>https://statsnips.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on StatSnips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 StatSnips. Distributed Under a MIT License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 21:12:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://statsnips.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cygwin Colors</title>
      <link>https://statsnips.github.io/2017/03/10/cygwin-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 21:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://statsnips.github.io/2017/03/10/cygwin-colors/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered that Mintty is a great way to make your Cygwin terminal prettier. Mintty made my conversation from Fedora to Windows 10 and Cygwin more palatable.
Like all Cygwin pacakges/add-ons you’ll have to install it using the Cygwin installer. You can find some quick instructions at HowToGeek.
While there are a number of themes out there, I really like this Base-16 inspired set. I’ve also done some other tweaks to make my Cygwin terminal behave like my Mac Terminal (such as transparency when not in focus).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash R on Oracle Grid Engine (JHPCE)</title>
      <link>https://statsnips.github.io/2016/12/20/bash-r-on-oracle-grid-engine-jhpce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 21:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://statsnips.github.io/2016/12/20/bash-r-on-oracle-grid-engine-jhpce/</guid>
      <description>I recently link posted on submitting Stata jobs to a Linux computing cluster running the Oracle Grid Engine. Here’s a quick post on how to submit a R job.
I usually submit a qsub job by writing qsub Scripts/NAME_OF_SCRIPT into terminal. My R scripts use the following naming convention: R&amp;lt;PROJECT&amp;gt;_v&amp;lt;NUM&amp;gt;.sh or R_018v1.sh for a R bash file to run the v1 R script in the 018 project (I explain my project organization in another post).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Stata on Oracle Grid Engine (JHPCE)</title>
      <link>https://statsnips.github.io/2016/12/20/bash-stata-on-oracle-grid-engine-jhpce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 21:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://statsnips.github.io/2016/12/20/bash-stata-on-oracle-grid-engine-jhpce/</guid>
      <description>Some statistical jobs are either too memory-greedy or computationally intensive to run on a local machine. At the Johns Hopkins Medical Institutes (JHMI), researchers have access to a Linux cluster running a Oracle Grid Enginge (previously called the Sun Grid Engine).
Jobs on the Joint HPC Exchange (JHPCE) can be run interactively with the qrsh command or through a qsub bash submission. JHPCE also has Stata-MP installed so that’s another reason why I use it for larger jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>